本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译 米小勒   kiko   Marshal同学  CS小明漫画家   H小欠
翻译   章鱼   我叫魏碧慧   蔡茸茸   S很爱笑   迷失   小奶
时间轴   贝贝   芒果树叶   SumenQ     后期   小亲斤
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第十集
北极光阵地  国家安全局指令中心
知晓着一大波僵尸在行进中  我还没有B-52轰炸机
Knowing some damn zombies on the march and me without a B-52.
适当地补上几颗核弹
A few well placed nukes and
搞不好人类就又重回轨道了
the human race is back in business.
别跟我扯什么殃及无辜
Oh, don't talk to me about collateral damage.
放弃几个人可以拯救全人类嘛
The death of the few for the good of the many.
我懂得  我懂得啦
I know, I know.
我又在胡言乱语啦
I'm talking out of my ass again.
我不会去核爆任何人的
I'm not nuking anybody.
反正今日是不会的
Not today anyhow.
但做做白日梦又何妨呢是吧
But a man can dream, right?
估计这会儿  也就只有"咬痕"研究所
Meanwhile, I guess it's up to operation Bite Mark
可以拯救人类了
to save humanity.
如果能知道他们在哪
I'd feel a hell of a lot better
感觉就会好多了
if I knew where they were.
我这想法不错吧  二哈
Pretty good, right dog?
矮油  你又不懂的啦
Awww, you don't know.
布莱克山  南达科他州
不会这整个州都需要爬坡吧
Is this entire state uphill?
我们现在到底在哪
Where are we anyway?
根据这地图显示  我们身处南达科他州的布莱克山上
According to this map, we're in the Black Hills of South Dakota.
我想念以前的卡车了
I miss the truck.
起码我们远离了那一大群恶心鬼
At least we're out of that damn horde.
可这儿没什么丧尸可杀了呢...
There's nothing to kill out here.
这点姐可不介意
That's fine by me.
我们需要赶紧找个地方落脚
We need to find a place to make camp soon.
哥的老蹄子蹬不动了
My dogs is getting tired.
这附近应该有个叫埃奇蒙特的小镇
Well there's supposed to be a little town nearby called Edgemont.
我会在下个山脊这儿看一下罗盘度数
I'll take a compass reading at this next ridge up here.
我们就不能先歇下吗
Can't we just take a break?
歇一小下吧
A quick one.
天呐
Oh my God.
快看
Look.
到底那是谁做的啊
Now who in the hell did that?
一些有着变态幽默感的冒失鬼们吧
Some daredevil with a sick sense of humor.
那是拉什莫尔山吗
Is that Mount Rushmore?
这就是为何我们不能创造美好的事物
This is why we can't have nice things.
估计是之前毁坏自由钟那混蛋的又一杰作吧
Probably the same jackass that tagged the Liberty Bell.
我觉得很赞哦
I think it's awesome.
如果让姐抓到了肇事者
If I ever catch who did that,
姐抽不死丫的
they're gonna get a whoopin'.
快点吧  我们得去找那个镇了
Come on. Let's find that town.
天马上要黑了
It's gonna get dark soon.
我还以为要歇一下呢
I thought we were taking a break.
休息结束了
Break time's over.
我们都走了几小时了
We've been walking for hours.
承认吧  "哥伦布"大姐  你走迷路了
Admit it, Columbus, you're lost.
别BB了  墨菲
Give it a rest, Murphy.
沃伦知道要往哪里走
Warren knows where she's going.
你知道要往哪里走的哈  沃伦
You know where you're going, Warren?
额  按理说走到这会儿本该走到了
Well we should've hit the town by now.
同时在此声明
And for the record,
哥伦布当时发现美洲大陆时也迷路了
Columbus was lost when he discovered America.
呵呵  大姐  您给自己台阶铺得真好
Yeah, and look how that turned out.
快看看那儿
Check this out.
那也不是镇子啊
That's not a town.
作为一名乐观开朗  积极向上的医生
Well now being Doctor Brightside for the moment,
我觉得里面或许会有些有用的东西
maybe there's something useful inside.
是啊  过去看看吧
Yeah. Let's check it out.
呵呵  真有家的感觉呢
Oh, just like home.
你知道吗  这个地方对我们而言  或许是个
You know what, this actually might be a safe place
安全的落脚处  还能搞到些补给
for us to get some rest and load up on some supplies.
我还能睡上一小时
I could use an hour's sleep.
多克  去开门
Hey. Doc, get the door.
这年头还锁什么门嘛
Why do they still lock doors?
幸好我有把万能钥匙
Luckily I have a skeleton key.
作为一名消极悲观的医生
Well being Doctor Darkside,
看来我们在这里是找不到食物或者弹药了
we are not gonna find much food or ammo in here.
没错  要是我们想找工业管道
Yeah. If we wanted industrial pipes,
那就是来对地方了
this would be the place to be.
真讨厌
I don't like this.
快看啊
Oh, look.
打住  你不能就这样喝了
Hey, hey, hold on. You can't just drink that.
你不会以为这里是小超市吧
What do you think this is the local Piggly Wiggly?
这可能是什么工业用水
That could be some kind of you know industrial type water
喝了会穿肠烂肚
that'll rot your insides.
少废话
Spare me the details.
看这里
Shhh, over there.
快躲起来
Take cover. Come on.
大家都别出声
Everybody sit quietly.
抱歉
Sorry.
屁走火了
It got away from me.
要是我因为你放屁而挂掉  我就拉你垫背
If I die because you farted, I am taking you with me.
这尼玛是什么呀
What in the livin' hell?
还夜光的呢
It's glowin'.
就像个僵尸鬼
It's like a zombie ghost.
它为什么会发光
Why is he glowing?
它还有同伴
He's got friends.
该死
Shoot.
别碰它们
Don't touch them!
离僵尸远点  这么近很危险
Back away from the Zs! It's not safe!
不行
No!
别碰它们
Don't touch them!
会传染吗
Are they contagious?
它们有放射性
Radioactive.
放射性
Radioactive?
怎么可能
How is that possible?
我带你去看
I'll show you.
自己看吧
There you go.
他们今日还真是不走运啊
This is gonna be one of them days, ain't it?
容我问一句
If you don't mind my asking,
你们在反应堆附近瞎转悠什么
what were you folks doing wandering out there near the reactor?
我们迷路了
We were lost.
我们没迷路
We weren't lost.
我们的车在距这里二十英里的地方跑没油了
Our vehicle ran out of gas 20 miles from here.
为了躲开僵尸我们从树林里抄了小路
We took a shortcut through the woods so we could avoid the Zs.
那算你们找对路了
You're not lost anymore.
欢迎来到南达科他州的埃奇蒙特
Welcome to Edgemont, South Dakota.
不算上你们  这里只住了三个人
Population three, not counting you.
我叫威尔伯·格雷迪
Name's Wilbur Grady.
这是我女儿艾米莉亚
This is my daughter, Amelia.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
幸会  我是罗伯塔·沃伦
Nice meeting you. I'm Roberta Warren.
他是摩菲
This is Murphy.
她是卡桑德拉  后面的是一万
And that's Cassandra. And this is 10K in the back.
他还好吧
Is he okay?
不太好  辐射病
No. Radiation poisoning.
我很好
I'm fine.
让我帮你们检查一下
Let's get you folks checked out
给你们搞点吃的
and get you some food.
我们家就在离路口不远的地方
Our place is just around here down the road a little ways.
这是什么
What are these?
碘片
Iodine.
它能防止辐射累积在你的甲状腺内
It'll keep the radiation from accumulating in your thyroid.
对  没错
Yeah, right.
看起来你们身上的辐射量还在正常范围内
Looks like you're still within safe levels.
不过你们该庆幸我们救援及时
But you're lucky we came along when we did.
这里绝大部分僵尸都有高度放射性
Most of the Zs around here are highly radioactive.
好像变成吃脑子的僵尸还不够糟似得
As if being brain-eating zombies wasn't bad enough.
我有个问题要问
Okay. Question.
我们也应该穿上防护服吧
Shouldn't we be in one of these suits too?
这里的辐射强度没那么大
Radiation levels aren't too bad out here.
不过接下来20年里  你们可能会得癌症
But you'll probably get cancer in twenty years.
我倒不太担心这个
Somehow that's way down on my list of worries.
但我们现在面临一个棘手的问题
Yeah, but our more immediate problem
核反应堆芯即将融毁
is the reactor core melting down.
如果我们不尽快修好
We don't fix it soon,
三百英里范围内的所有东西都会发光
then everything within a 300 mile radius will be glowing.
不只是那些僵尸
Not just the Zs.
既然这样
Okay, well
很高兴见到你们
it's been nice meeting you.
我们也有别的地方要去
We have places to be,
那些地方离这里绝对不止三百英里
places at least 300 miles from here.
那祝你好运
Good luck with that.
镇上所有的车都被开走了
Every vehicle in town is gone
剩下的都不能开了
or can't be driven.
我认为我们现在最好是步行上路了
Then I guess we better start walking.
你走不出去的
You won't make it.
还有不到48小时堆芯就会融毁
We have less than 48 hours before the core starts to melt down.
那你们为什么还留在这里
Why are you still here?
因为还有一线希望
Because there's still a chance to shut this thing down
关掉它就可以挽救大片上帝的国度
and save a big chunk of God's country
接下来一万年内免遭辐射之灾
from being irradiated for the next 10,000 years.
而且  我离死也不远了
Besides I'm already a goner.
那令媛呢
Well what about your daughter?
她也为这个自杀任务签下生死状吗
Did she sign up for this suicide mission too?
我一直会陪在父亲身边  帮助他
I am sticking around to help my dad.
我跟她说过  我不需要她的帮助
I told her I didn't need her help,
她就是不听
but she wouldn't listen.
我是一名飞行员
I'm a pilot.
我可以用飞机把大家带出危险区
I'll fly us out of the hot zone.
那太好了
Well perfect.
我们搭个顺风车
We'll just hitch a ride.
没错
Yeah.
如你们所见  机上只能坐一名乘客
As you can see there's only room for one passenger.
我的子弹也够给你们每人一枪
And I have enough bullets for all of you,
所以不要再打飞机的主意了
so don't go getting any ideas.
格雷迪...威尔伯先生
Mister Grady, Wilbur.
虽然你可能看不出来
I know it doesn't look like it,
但这个人
but this man...
他是唯一已知被僵尸咬伤后还能活下来的人
this man is the only known survivor of a zombie bite.
我还以为他有什么问题
Thought there was something wrong with him.
他的血液里有僵尸病毒的抗体
His blood carries antibodies for the zombie virus.
他是全人类最后的希望
He's our last best hope for humanity.
那哥还是复活节的小兔子呢
Yeah right, and I'm the Easter bunny.
给他看看
Show him.
我的上帝
Oh my God.
老兄  你看
Now look, man.
这哥们可是如假包换的
This dude here's the real deal.
很多人为了护送他而丧命
And a lot of people got killed getting him this far.
所以你告诉我们怎么做才能关闭反应堆
So tell us what we need to do to shut down that reactor
大家才能继续上路
so we can be on our way.
除非你还要忙着下蛋  兔子先生
Unless of course you have eggs to lay, Mister Bunny.
我的计划是这样的
Okay, here's the plan.
我要进到控制室里面
I need to get to the control room
看看是否可以搞清楚
to see if I can figure out
燃料棒无法正常落入冷却池
why the fuel rods aren't dropping down
阻止核反应的原因
to the cooling pool to stop the reaction.
因为里面僵尸太多
I haven't been able to get in there
我根本进不去
cuz of this gauntlet of zombies.
所以我需要你们的帮助
That's where I need your help.
杀僵尸  我们行
Killing zombies, that's what we do.
核反应堆保护壳外面的辐射强度
Radiation levels are only slightly elevated
只是高那么一点点
outside the containment building.
所以至少两分钟之内是安全的
So you should be safe for at least two minutes.
在你不得不退回来之前
Long enough to get me to the door
有足够的时间协助我到门那里
before you have to retreat back here.
禁止停车  不要堵门
用一切手段
Use whatever you have
阻止僵尸靠近
to keep the Zs from getting too close.
它们受到了严重污染
They're very contaminated.
跟他们拥抱一下  你就只剩几小时可活了
One hug and you'll be dead in a few hours.
不要抱僵尸
Don't hug the zombies.
懂了
Got it.
你们俩待在这
You two stay here.
一万  你从上面掩护我们
10K, you cover us from up there.
如果我们回不来  你必须想办法送他去加州
If we don't get back, you get him to California somehow.
来吧孩子  准备好了吗
Come kid, you ready?
上吧
Let's do this.
一万
10k!
第2304个
Two thousand, three hundred and four.
记住  两分钟  不能再长了
Remember two minutes! No more!
上
Go!
快跟上
Come on!
你们还有一分钟
You got one more minute!
不要拥抱哥啦
No hugging!
快上来吧  我们走
Come on, let's go!
你们得走了
Time for you to go.
你们必须撤了
You got to go.
撤
Go!
注意了
Heads up!
我来搞定
I got it.
出去吧
Get out of here.
你们没时间了
You're out of time.
你们必须撤出去  撤
You have to go. Go.
他们回来了
They're back.
我快到控制室了
I'm almost to the control room.
太好了  继续  爸爸
Great. Keep going, dad.
我们现在做什么
What do we do now?
等他
We wait.
咬痕研究所  这里是北极光  呼叫
Operation Bitemark, this is Northern Light, come in.
咬痕研究所  这里是北极光  是否收到
Operation Bitemark, this is Northern Light, do you copy?.
咬痕研究所  这里是北极光  呼叫
Operation Bitemark, this is Northern Light, come in.
咬痕研究所  这里是北极光  是否收到
Operation Bitemark, this is Northern Light, do you copy?.
咬痕研究所  这里是北极光  呼叫
Operation Bitemark, this is Northern Light, come in.
咬痕研究所  这里是北极光
Operation Bitemark, this is Northern Light,
-是否收到  -乖孩子
- do you copy. - Good Boy.
咬痕研究所
Operation Bitemark.
他来了
Hey, here he comes.
爸爸
Dad.
爸爸  爸爸  爸爸  爸爸
Dad, dad, dad, dad.
爸爸  你没事吧
Dad, are you okay?
看着我  爸爸
Look at me, dad.
-我没成功  -爸爸  爸爸  不  不
- I didn't make it. - Dad, dad, no, no.
不  挺住  挺住  挺住
No, hang on, hang on, hang on.
爸爸  不  不
Dad. No! No!
不  爸爸
No! Daddy.
不  醒醒  求你了
No. Wake up. Please.
字幕
No!
不  不  不不  求你  不要死  爸爸
No! No! No, no, please, no, not you dad!
不  不  不
No! No! No!
不
No.
不要死
Not you.
很抱歉  把他埋了吧
I'm sorry. Let's bury him.
不
No.
看起来那东西还是过热
So that thing is still read to cook off.
我想知道现在我们该做什么
Well I'd like to know what we're supposed to do about it.
逃走行不通
Can't run.
我们逃不出爆炸范围
We're still within the blast zone.
我们进去
We go in.
进去干什么
And do what?
知道怎么关闭那玩意儿的是格雷迪
Grady was the one who knew how to shut that thing off.
我是医生  该死的
I'm a doctor, dammit,
又不是核物理学家
not a nuclear physicist.
就差一点
He was so close.
你爸爸做了个很好的尝试
Your dad gave it a good try.
有时候我们能做的也仅限于此
Sometimes that's the best we can do.
起码他没有死于他害怕的东西
It wasn't dying that he was afraid of.
他真的不想变成僵尸
He really didn't want to become a Z,
哪怕只有几秒
even for a few seconds.
艾米莉亚  我们需要知道
Amelia, we need to know...
如果我们保护你  你能不能
can you shut this thing down by yourself
独自关掉那玩意儿
if we protect you?
我了解飞机
I know airplanes,
不是核电站
not nukes.
棒极了
Awesome.
但有一个人知道
I mean there's one guy.
在这吗  在埃奇蒙特吗
Here, here in Edgemont?
是的  荷马·斯塔宾斯
Yeah, Homer Stubbins.
他在核电站做了二十年的总工程师
He was the chief engineer at the plant for 20 years.
他是我爸爸的上司
He was dad's boss.
末世开始之后他就躲进了森林里
He's been holed up in the woods since the apocalypse.
他有武器  是个危险人物
He's armed and dangerous.
他儿子死后他就开始隐居
He became a recluse after the death of his son.
我们怎么才能找到荷马
How do we find Homer?
他不会理你们的
He won't talk to you.
我们得试试
We have to try.
我们只能走到这了
We have to stop here.
还有五十码远呢
We're still fifty yards away.
我爸爸说这里设了地雷
My dad said the place was booby-trapped.
我跟你们说过了  荷马是个疯子
I told you, Homer's crazy.
我们完全不考虑先去打个电话吗
Have we completely dismissed the idea of a phone call?
我就随便一说
Just sayin'.
这种陷阱是你的风格
This is your kinda set-up.
我们怎么能进去
How do we get in?
是活着进去
Without us getting killed.
我希望你们把这个谨记于心
I do like to keep that in mind.
有一点很重要
Uh, well one thing.
荷马的陷阱旨在阻止僵尸  而非正常人
Homer's set-up is aimed at stopping Zs, not a team.
所以如果我们擦亮眼睛看清地雷和拉发线
So if we keep a sharp eye out for landmines, trip wires...
就不会有事
We'll be fine.
好的
Okay.
你们三个  留在这里
The three of you guys, stay here.
让我们先走四十秒
Give us a 40 second head start.
我们从侧面绕过去由后门进
We'll flank him and come up from behind.
好的  小心地雷
Okay, watch for mines.
看着呢
Watching them.
别动
Don't move!
你有三秒钟的时间告诉我你们在这干什么
You have three seconds to tell me what you're doing here.
一
One.
二
Two.
别轻举妄动  先生
Don't do that, sir.
动手吧  但是帮我个忙
Go ahead. Do me a solid.
别让我变成僵尸
Just don't leave me a Z.
我不会的  斯塔宾斯先生
I'd never do that, Mr. Stubbins.
我们只是需要你帮忙
We just need your help.
大爷  您也好啊
Hello to you too.
格雷迪是个好人
Grady was a good man.
如果说有人可以"安控斧"反应堆
If anyone could SCRAM that reactor
那就是他
it was him.
"安控斧"
Scram?
安全控制棒持斧人
Safety Control Rod Axe Man.
这要追溯到第一个反应堆
Goes back to the first reactors.
他们拥有的唯一安全系统差不多就是
The only safety system they had was literally
一个人一把斧子
a man with an axe
等到熔毁事故发生时  他只需要
whose whole job in the event of a meltdown
砍断悬在冷却池上方燃料棒上的绳子
was to cut the rope holding fuel rods over the cooling pool.
我爸就是想这么做的
That's what dad was trying to do.
你还有多少时间
How much time do you have?
是我们还有多少时间好吧
How much time do we have?
你跟我们在一条船上  荷马
You're in the soup with us, Homer.
你是不是把我和别的关心这事的人搞混了
You've confused me with someone who gives a damn.
据格雷迪说  不到40小时了
According to Grady, less than 40 hours.
我们还就是关心这事呢
And we do give a damn.
你是打算帮我们
Now are you gonna help us
还是这么干坐着眼看大家全玩完
or are you gonna sit here and let us all die?
有个办法倒可以一试
Well there's one thing we might try.
我得带你们去看看
I'm gonna have to show you.
我们需要武器  设备
We're gonna need weapons, equipment.
来吧  装备起来
Come on. Load up.
反正这些个东西我也用不着了
It's not as if I'm gonna be needing this stuff.
你好啊  救星
Hello, nurse.
上等伏特加  僵尸天启特供延命水
Vitamin V. The elixir of the Zombie Apocalypse.
你正在看的是反应堆的
You know you're looking at the original building plans
最初设计图
for this reactor.
我当初也是设计团队的一员
I was part of the design team.
你年纪轻轻的  一把刀使起来
You're pretty handy with that knife
倒挺溜
for a kid.
我儿子...
My son...
他也有把这样的刀
he had one like it
不过刀刃更长
but with a longer blade.
对  是老款的
Yeah, older model.
想用好这刀需要不少技巧
Got to be good to make it work.
马克斯很厉害
Oh, Max was good.
我们走  出发吧
Okay, let's go, let's do it.
我听说了你儿子的事了
I heard about your son.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
再没有比白发人送黑发人更惨的事了
There's nothing worse than outliving your own child.
没了
Nothing.
南达科他一带还真是静的不得了啊  是不是
There sure is a whole lot of nothing in South Dakota, huh boy?
见鬼
Dammit.
卫星电话
侦测到通讯
什么鬼
What the hell?
一通卫星电话
A satellite phone?
是那小队的吗
Is it my team?
该死
Oh, rats.
通讯中断
北极光  请回答
Northern Light, come in.
我不知道你用那破玩意儿打算联系谁
I don't know what you want with that old piece of junk.
还能打给谁呢
Nobody to call.
我们知道有人没准会接
We got somebody that might pick up.
北极光  请回答
Northern Light, come in.
有什么不对吗  荷马
Something wrong, Homer?
我认识她
I knew her, that's all.
她儿子是马克斯的好朋友
Her son was one of Max's buddies.
你们知不知道重回你童年的老房子
Did you ever go back to the house you grew up in
却只能亲眼见到它颓败倒塌是什么感觉
only to see it's falling apart and in a bad neighborhood?
现在就是这种感觉
That's what this feels like.
再扩大十倍
Times ten.
在我老家  僵尸实在是改善市容市貌了
Well where I grew up, the Zombie Apocalypse only improved things.
好  说正事吧
All right, back to business.
过了这道围栏就有辐射了  对吧
From here on the area's hot, right?
你们有两套防辐射服
You got two clean rad suits in there.
一套我用
One for me and
我还需要有个人支援我
I need somebody to back me up.
不  我去
No. I'll go.
你不能去啊
Well you can't go.
万一出了岔子
Who's gonna get him to California
谁把他送到加州呢
if something goes wrong?
别指望哥啊
Don't look at me.
好吧  那行
Okay. All right.
你要记住你现在是有子弹
Just remember you have ammo now.
但子弹也有用完的时候
But not an infinite supply.
我们上吧
Let's do this.
禁止入内
我们得找到控制室
We made it to the control room.
问题的关键就在那儿
And there's our problem.
三号冷却池
Cooling pool three.
你能让它紧急停止吗
Can you SCRAM it or not?
根据控制系统显示  所有的燃料棒都启用了
According to the controls, all the rods are enabled
但是有东西卡在了嵌入处
but something is physically blocking the insertion.
必须把那东西清理掉
We need to remove it.
徒手吗
By hand?
不需要我们亲自来
Not by our hand.
它叫罗比
This is Robbie.
它能开进核芯  进行手动紧急停堆
He will roll into the core and do a manual SCRAM.
它能穿透任何东西
He can cut through anything.
这个小宝贝甚至能让钢铁蒸发
This little darlin' can vaporize steel.
我懂了
I get it.
就像无人机一样
It's like a drone.
只不过它从来不在天上飞
Only he never leaves the ground.
僵尸太多了
There's too many Zs.
退回去吧  荷马
Back it up, Homer.
我来操作
I'll do the driving.
我们必须前进
We need to go forward.
该死被僵尸发现了
Damn Zs got us.
你长得可真丑啊
You're an ugly one.
去死吧
Damn Z.
我没时间陪你玩
I don't have time for this.
快干掉他们
Get 'em out of there.
该死的僵尸  滚开
Damn Z. Leave.
罗比阵亡了
We lost Robbie.
现在怎么办
So what now?
采用方案二还是方案三
Plan B or is it C?
要不就是方案四  五  六
Give me a D, E, F.
别说些没用的
Not helpful.
好吧  罗比坏了
All right. Robbie failed.
但我还是能手动停堆
But I can still do a manual SCRAM.
怎么做  里面全都是僵尸
How? That place is filled with Zs.
我们重装上阵
We'll go in heavier.
这次我们一起上
Take us along this time.
我们可能还有一次紧急停堆的机会
We probably only got one more shot at a SCRAM.
但必须先穿上重型保护装才能进控制室
But we'll need heavier suits to reach the control room.
去哪儿找那些保护装
Where do we find them?
在实验室里  离刚才罗比被干掉的地方不远
In the lab, not far from where we lost Robbie.
可以去四个人  两个人穿这种保护装
Four can go in, two in these suits.
我跟这小子穿重型保护装
Me and the kid in the heavies.
好啊
Okay.
不过要是方案三也不中用
But what happens if plan C doesn't work
我们最后都被核辐射弄死了怎么办
and we wind up with our very own Fukushima Chernobyl whatever?
你是担心你自己遭遇不测吧
You mean what happens to you?
喂  我可没有主动请缨拯救人类
I didn't ask for the job of saving the human race.
艾米莉亚
Amelia.
你能不能开飞机把他带到放射区外
Would you be willing to fly him out of the radiation zone?
说实话
To be honest,
飞机燃料不够了
I don't have enough fuel.
我跟我爸撒谎了
I lied to my dad or else
要不然他是不会让我留下来的
he never would have let me stay behind.
好极了
Great.
不过要是有几加仑燃油的话
If I had a few gallons,
我就能带上一个人离开爆炸区
I might be able to get myself and one other person
这说的还是最幸运的情况
outside the blast zone, if we are lucky.
以前  我跟朋友把一辆道奇·达特轿车
Okay, a buddy and I once converted a Dodge Dart
改装成烧酒精的了
to run on alcohol.
一架轻型飞机的发动机也没多少不同
A light plane engine isn't that different.
你有很多伏特加
You had a serious supply of vodka.
任你取用
You're welcome to it.
好的
Okay.
多克和卡桑德拉
Doc and Cassandra,
跟一万和荷马一队  你们掩护他们
go with 10K and Homer. You cover them.
摩菲和艾米莉亚跟我来
Murphy and Amelia, come with me.
考虑到没有其它选择
Given we have no other choices,
我还是接受这个安排吧
I shall embrace the inevitable.
如果行得通  我们就回到这里庆功
If this works, we'll meet back here to celebrate.
危险
情况不妙啊  爆炸前我们只有30分钟
That's not good. We have 30 minutes till boom.
勇敢的小家伙
Brave little dude.
真糟糕  只能把他留在这里了
Too bad we have to leave him here like this.
在这个丑陋的世界里
Sentiment is a fatal flaw
多愁善感可是致命的缺点
in this ugly world.
以防需要支援
We should let Warren know where we are
应该让沃伦知道我们到哪了  对吧
in case we need backup, right?
沃伦  我是多克
Warren, this is Doc.
请注意  我们已经进入到
Please be advised we have entered the tunnel
通往反应堆芯的隧道了
to the reactor core.
通话完毕
Over and out.
我们看看这个宝贝出什么毛病了
Let's see what's going on with this baby.
亲爱的  艾米莉亚
So Amelia, my dear.
我们靠着这堆完好的航空硬件
Where exactly might we be headed
到底要飞到哪里
in this fine piece of aeronautical hardware?
考虑到这可是涉及到我的性命
Considering it's only my life
以及人类存亡的关键
and the human race at stake.
谢里丹  怀俄明州
Sheridan, Wyoming.
我们向西北方向飞
It's to the northwest,
放射性尘埃会被吹向东南方
and the fallout will be to the southeast.
两个方向相距甚远
Far enough away, and
我和爸爸还听说那里有人类存活
my dad and I heard there's some real humans.
希望它能飞起来
I just hope it works.
小菜一碟  给我一些工具就行了
Piece of cake. All I need is some tools.
摩菲  你能不能别喝燃料了
Murphy, could you quit drinking your fuel
然后给油箱加满
and fill up the damn tank?
我不知道油箱在哪
I don't know where the tank is.
反正不是在你嘴里
Well it's not in your mouth.
给我一个螺丝刀
Let me get a screwdriver.
好吧  飞机里有22加仑燃料
Okay, so that was 22 gallons.
这里到谢里丹的直线距离是250英里
Sheridan is 250 miles as the crow flies.
这里还有两瓶
Here's a couple more.
那里距离爆炸区足够远吗
Is that gonna be far enough to clear the blast zone?
肯定够了
It'll have to be.
这是伏特加  不是航空燃油
Well this is vodka, not avgas.
所以实际里程数可能存在变数
So the mileage may vary.
听着  我...
Listen, I, uhhh...
该死  你不是要跟我道别吧
Oh shit, you're not gonna try and say goodbye, are you?
我本想说
I was going to say
面对每个人的牺牲  要有感恩之心
be grateful for all the sacrifices everyone has made.
看你的了
Back at you.
我们到了吗
Are we there yet?
我们只飞了5分钟好吗
We've been in the air for five minutes.
我有点喜欢飞行了  这里看不到僵尸
You know, I kinda like this. You can't see any zombies.
我打赌  他们就在下面
They're down there, bet on it.
如果我们能在比林斯找到更多燃料
Hey, if we find more fuel in Billings,
我们可以再次起飞  直达加利福尼亚
we could take off again and head to California.
我们要找的是伏特加
If we find vodka.
我可不知道如何将烧酒精的发动机再改回烧燃油的
I don't know how to change this carburetor back to a gas-burner.
多克  我是沃伦  现在回到工厂了
Doc, this is Warren, back at the plant,
准备按同样路线进入
coming in the same way.
多克  我是沃伦
Doc, Warren.
你好  罗伯塔  欢迎归队
Hello, Roberta. Welcome back.
请注意  我们现在从设施的另一端
Please be advised we're now entering the reactor core
进入反应堆芯
on the other side of the facility.
有什么我能做的吗
Is there something I can do?
为我们祈祷吧
Oh, just the usual prayer.
我们的"贵重货物"怎么样了
What's the status of that precious cargo?
那个"话唠包裹"起飞了吗
Has the mouthy package taken off?
是的  已经飞上天了
Yeah, he's in the air.
那等我们解决掉麻烦
Then we'll fix our little problem.
出去再跟你会合吧
And see you on the way out.
你会记挂你的朋友们吗
Will you miss your friends?
他们不是我的朋友
They're not my friends.
顶多算是临时战友
More like foxhole buddies.
但是  会想念的
But yeah.
-怎么回事  等一下  -我...
- What's going on? Wait. - I...
-什么情况  -我能搞定
- What is that? - I got it.
只是遇到气流  颠簸了一下
Just a little turbulence.
我的妈呀
Oh God!
稳住
Hang on.
-闭嘴  给我坐稳  -我的妈呀
- Shut up and hang on! - Oh God!
我的天啊
Oh God!
艾米莉亚
Amelia!
天啊  不是吧
Oh God, no.
施以仁慈
Mercy.
好奇怪
It's weird.
太诡异了
It's too weird.
来瞧瞧
All right.
看哪辆车还能启动可以带我们离开这里
Which one of you fine vehicles is our ride out of here?
你好  三角洲X光小队
Hello, Delta-X-Ray.
这是三角洲X光小队  收到请回复
This is Delta-X-Ray, copy.
给我一些发光僵尸的信息
I need a little information on glowing zombies.
好的  正在查找"僵尸百科"
Okay. Checking zombie-pedia.
你开玩笑呢
Are you kidding?
是的  不过这也不失为一个好主意
For now, but it's not a bad idea.
查到了  这叫"天使之光"
Okay. It's called 'Angel's Glow.'
源自于一种线虫细菌
Comes from nematode bacteria.
不知何故  放射物感染了僵尸的皮肤
Somehow the radiation affects zombie skin
在上面培养出了细菌
and lets bacteria grow there.
细菌暴露在高强度的辐射之下时就会发光
The bacteria glows when exposed to high levels of radiation.
首次出现是在日本的福岛
First observed at Fukushima.
你就回答我  他们会辐射吗
I just need an answer. Are they hot or not?
千万别让他们
Don't let them
喷溅到你
spatter you.
该死
Shoot.
你还在吗
Still there?
对
Yeah.
姐还能去哪儿
I got no other place to be.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
这衣服快把我焖熟了
Like a baked potato in this thing.
反应堆的堆芯就在这条通道的下面
Reactor core is right down this corridor.
那我们还愣在这儿干嘛
Then why are we standing here?
因为那里的放射强度太高了
Because it's highly radioactive in there.
我要下到堆芯里  手动插入操作杆
I'm going into the core to manually insert those rods.
凭你一人之力吗
By yourself?
别挡道  小家伙
Out of my way, sonny.
不好意思  你需要后援
I'm sorry. You need backup.
随你便吧
Suit yourself.
你们去吧  这事就交给我了
You guys go. I've got it.
拿着这个
Take this.
随时跟我们汇报情况
And we need to hear everything!
好了  走吧  行动
All right! Go on! Move it!
快点
Come on!
不知他从哪儿冒出来的  我没反应过来
That guy came out of nowhere. I couldn't move fast enough.
这是一个好消息伴随着各种噩耗的状况吧
It's one of those good news, really really bad news things.
没被咬死  但防护服破了
The suit is breached.
能拿胶带粘上吗
Can I tape it up?
孩子  我这辈子吸收的辐射量太多了
Son, I've accumulated so many rads in my life,
我走向大门的那一刻
I was probably a dead man
可能已经注定要牺牲了
the moment I walked through the gate.
我肯定能做点什么
There's got to be something I can do.
刚才那个你不算上吗
Aren't you gonna add to your count?
第2316个
Two thousand three hundred and sixteen.
你知道吗  你是个好孩子
You know you're a good kid,
跟我儿子马克斯一样坚强和聪明
strong, smart, like my son Max.
我希望上帝能给你更好的运气
I just hope to God you have better luck.
你也挺像我爸爸的
You're a lot like my dad too.
有一样的厄运
With the same bad luck.
为了大家你得活下去
You need to go on for all of us.
答应我
Promise me that.
继续生活...我儿子已经做不到了
Live the life...my son never had.
我们得到上面去
We need to get up there.
所剩的时间不多了
Time really is a waistin'.
让我们搞定它吧
Let's get to it.
这就是我们的麻烦
There's our problem.
有两条棒没下去
Two rods didn't go down.
我得过去手动把它们分开
I'm gonna have to go out there and unstick those rods.
小心别把我扔到反应堆里
Be careful not to drop me into the reactor pool.
我会马上被煮熟的
I'll be cooked instantly.
我们不该让他们孤军作战
We shouldn't have left them alone.
收到
Got it.
我们无法留下  那超出了我们的极限
We couldn't stay. We were at our limits.
那玩意儿爆炸了  也没啥极限可谈了
That thing goes off and limits won't matter.
荷马知道自己在做什么
Homer knows what he's doing.
而且我们小万万很棒的好吗
And the kid is awesome.
我出发了
Here I go.
你能让我靠近点吗
Can you get me closer?
好的  对不起
Yeah, sorry.
我以为你这个时代的人都是遥控高手
I thought everybody your age was a whiz with a remote.
我不是
Not me.
再把我放低一点
Lower me a little more.
你能让我再靠近点吗
Can you get me a little closer?
好
Okay.
按下写着"释放控制爪"的开关
Now hit the switch that says claw release.
一个下去了
One down.
等这个搞定了
Once this is fixed,
毙了我然后逃出去
shoot me and get out.
我不想成为它们的一员
I don't want to become one of them.
如果我最近没说什么
If I haven't said anything lately,
我想说非常感谢宇宙
thank you so much,universe.
赐予我僵尸天启
For the Zombie Apocalypse!
莫奇医生还有我的人生遭遇
And for Doctor Merch and my whole situation!
还有...不知道还有什么...走着瞧
And for, well I don't know, let's see, what else.
荒废的核电站
The Badlands Nuclear Power Plant!
还有对了
And yes!
多亏你  宇宙
Points to you, universe!
多亏你一路把我
Points to you for dragging my ass
拖曳来南达科塔找死
all the way to South Dakota to die!
那真是天大的讽刺啊
That was sarcasm.
我跟其他人不一样
I am not like other boys.
我不会施以仁慈的
I do not give mercy.
回去吧
Go home!
哥没有什么可以给你
I don't have anything for you!
你就找不到别人咬了吗
Can't you find somebody to munch on?
我的妈呀
Oh God,
还真的是丧尸界的小呆萌
really is puppies and kittens.
再过去...两...英寸
Two...more...inches.
现在再打开开关
Now hit the claw release again.
快  搞定了
Almost... there.
荷马  成功了
Homer, it worked.
怎么样
How about that?
咱们做得很好
We did good.
好了  我现在把你拉上来
All right, now let me get you out of there.
现在就杀了我吧
Shoot me now.
我已经杀了我爸爸  我不想再杀你了
I already killed my father. I don't want to kill you.
想说爱你也不容易啊
You don't make it easy.
不不不
No, no, no! No, no, no! No!
不
No!
他回来了
Here he comes.
孩子  等等  矮油  小万万
Hey, kid! Wait! Wait up!
荷马救了我们
Homer saved us!
没错  他救了整个小镇
That's right. He saved the whole town!
不是那样的
It's not that!
我救不了他
I couldn't save him.
我知道  我们都听到了
I know, I know. We heard.
你已经尽力了
You did everything you could.
你让他解脱了
You gave him mercy.
你让我回想起了我在好市多工作的前妻
You remind me of my ex-wife, back from Costco.
哪个女的会嫁给你啊
Who'd marry you?
哥老实告诉你  还真不少呢
Several women, I'll have you know.
不过她们要么没什么好品味
None with very good taste
要么没什么忍耐力
or staying power.
成功了吗
So it all worked.
我们安全了
We're safe.
至少不会融毁了
From the meltdown.
没别的了
Nothing else.
这个是充电器吗
Is this a battery charger?
是啊  我找不到能修好的卡车
Yeah. I couldn't find a truck that I could fix,
用这个估计能带我们走一段路
so that'll keep us going.
好吧  那我们能继续上路了
All right, so we can get back on the trail.
可是去哪呢
But where to?
咱们已经跟零号病患走散了
Given the fact that we've lost Patient Zero.
好消息
Great news!
伏特加真是个好燃料
The vodka made perfect fuel
十分钟就用了个精光
for ten minutes!
发生怎么了
What happened?
迫降了
Crash landing
在离小镇大概160公里的地方
about a hundred miles out of town.
你这可走了一大段路啊
Wow, you covered a lot of ground.
你是搭了个顺风车吗
Did you hitchhike?
好像是16公里  管他呢
Ten miles, whatever.
反正走路的时候感觉根本没有尽头
It felt like a hundred miles when you're walking.
那艾米莉亚呢
So what happened to Amelia?
不是吧
Oh no.
你没有仁慈地了结她吗
You didn't give her mercy?
不知道为什么  我感觉这样做不对
It didn't feel right, somehow.
你就让她一路跟着你吗
So you just let her follow you?
感觉...  这样...  比较好吧
That... felt... right, somehow.
好吧  你希望我们怎么做
Okay, what do you want us to do?
不不不
No, no! No, no, no, no, no! No!
不
No!
她不会伤害我们的
She is not hurting us!
我不知道
I don't know.
说不定我们应该尝试一下另一种仁慈
Maybe it's time for a different kind of mercy.
好吧
Okay.
上车吧
Climb aboard.